<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" ?>
<casaxml xmlns="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/psetTypes.html"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
    xsi:schemaLocation="http://casa.nrao.edu/schema/casa.xsd
    file:///opt/casa/code/xmlcasa/xml/casa.xsd">

    <task type="function" name="antintflag" category="editing">
        <shortdescription>Flags integrations if a specified antenna is flagged.</shortdescription>
        <description>
                
		This task will flag any integration in which all
		baselines to a specified antenna are flagged, but
		only if this condition is satisfied in greater than
		a nominated fraction of channels within the spectral
		window of interest.  All polarization products must be
		unflagged for antintflag to deem a baseline unflagged.
		
		This task also supports a channel mode where it will
		operate on a single channel in a nominated spectral
		window.  It will pass on any flagging to the entire
		spectral window.
		
		antintflag is only suitable for data in which the
		nominated antenna drops out occasionally (e.g. first
		few integrations of a scan due to slewing).
		
		An application in mind is removal of data that will
		otherwise lead to changes in reference antenna during
		gain calibration, which could in turn lead to corrupted
		polarization calibration.
		
		antintflag will report how much flagging was performed.
		However, this task will not back up existing flags;
		please do this manually using flagmanager (mode=save).
		
                Christopher A. Hales
                Version 1.0 (tested with CASA Version 4.7.0)
                27 October 2016
                
                Code available at: http://github.com/chrishales/antintflag
                antintflag is released under a BSD 3-Clause License;
                see LICENSE for details.
                
                
                
        </description>

        <input>
            <param type="string" name="vis" mustexist="true">
                <description>input MS or MMS</description>
                <value />
            </param>
            <param type="int" name="field">
                <description>field index number (not name)</description>
                <value>0</value>
            </param>
            <param type="string" name="spw">
                <description>spectral window with optional channel (e.g. \'0:7\')</description>
                <value>0</value>
            </param>
            <param type="string" name="ant">
                <description>antenna name (not index number)</description>
                <value>ea01</value>
            </param>
            <param type="double" name="minchanfrac">
                <description>min. fraction of channels with flagged antenna to initiate flagging</description>
                <value>0.6</value>
            </param>
            <param type="bool" name="verbose">
                <description>print timestamps of flagged integrations to the log</description>
                <value>False</value>
            </param>
        </input>

        <returns type="void"/>
        <example>

----- Detailed descriptions of keyword arguments -----


   Keyword arguments:
       
       
       antintflag does not support multiple index selection (e.g. field='0,2').
       In such cases, simply rerun antintflag for each index separately.
   
       
               vis -- Name of input MS or MMS.  This code will operate on the
                      'CORRECTED_DATA' column if available, else the 'DATA' column.
		      Circular and linear feed bases both supported, but if your
		      dataset is not simple (e.g. you use subscans, etc), then
		      antintflag probably won't work.
       
       
             field -- Field index number (integer).
       
       
               spw -- Spectral window with optional channel (string). For example,
                      '2' or '2:12', respectively.
       
       
               ant -- Antenna name (string).
       
       
       minchanfrac -- Minimum fraction of spw channels that must each contain
                      fully flagged baselines to the nominated antenna in order
		      for the integration of interest to be flagged.  Specify
		      between 0-1 (float).  minchanfrac will be ignored if spw
		      specifies a channel.
       
       
           verbose -- Print timestamps of flagged integrations to the log (boolean).
		      
       
       
        </example>
    </task>
</casaxml>
